# Ashwini Naik

PhD student at Electronic Visualization Laboratory at University of Illinois at Chicago. Currently conducting research on in-situ analysis of conversations in mixed and virtual reality along with research in visualization of complex scientific datasets. Diverse experience with scripting, programming, testing, troubleshooting, optimization and debugging.

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

Virtual/ Mixed Reality

**Data Visualization** 

Human Subjects Research

Unity/C#

## **Education**

University of Illinois at Chicago PhD in Computer Science Jan 2017 – Expected 2023 CGPA 3.7

University of Illinois at Chicago Master of Science in Computer Science Aug 2009 – Jul 2011 CGPA 3.12

R. N. S. Institute of Technology, Bangalore, INDIA Bachelor of Engineering in Information Science and Engineering Sep2003 – Jul 2007 68.84 %

## Relevant Coursework

Computer Graphics, Game Development, Computer Animation, User Interface Design, Visual Data Science, Visualization and Visual Analytics, Advanced Algorithms

## **Technical Skills**

Languages	Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, C#, C, Processing, GLSL
Web Design	HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery
Libraries and SDKs	D3.js, Three.js, React, <b>Unity</b> , Leap Motion, Open GL, CUDA, Vuforia, VRTK
Scripting	JavaScript, Python
Devices	HoloLens 1 & 2, Quest 1 and 2, HTC Vive, Magic Leap, Leap Motion, Oculus Rift
Databases	MySQL, Oracle 10g, SQL Server 2005/2008, Mongo dB (beginner)
Versioning	GitHub
ML/DL	Python, sklearn, nltk, keras, matlab, AWS

## Experience

## **Epsilon Data Management LLC**

May 2022 - Aug 2022

### **PhD Research Internship**

- ☐ Conducted research on Macro Path to Purchase Event Sequences.
- Implemented a new visualization component on a Peta Byte-level data analysis system
- ☐ Created interactive / responsive web components using state-of-the-art UI design principles
- Created api routes to access data for visualization component.

#### **Graduate Student, Electronic Visualization Laboratory**

- Teaching Assistant for CS 428 Virtual, Augmented and Mixed Reality; CS 425 Computer Graphics; CS 211 Programming Practicum II
- Conduct research on analysis of conversations using Mixed reality in smart collaborative environments
- Conduct research on **Visualization** of Dynamic Communities of Brain Networks using D3.js and Three.js
- ☐ Created V-NeuroStack application showing dynamic communities using 3D point cloud in three.js.
- Conduct research on a Machines Assisting Recovery from Stroke
- ☐ Implemented a game for Stroke Rehabilitation with Leap Motion device.
- Co-taught AR in journalism course at the Department of Communication, UIC

Scientific Games Jul 2012-Dec 2016

#### **Senior Test Engineer**

- ☐ Set up Engineering Customer Support team for India location
- Created training plans and trained associate test engineers
- ☐ Worked and resolved issues from the field that improved revenue in several casinos across jurisdictions
- Carried out team lead duties for ECS India

### Olenick and Associates Client: Chicago Mercantile Exchange

Jul 2011 - Mar 2012

### **Automation Engineer**

- Enhanced the existing Automation framework
- ☐ Maintained the automation testing framework for EOS Trader CME Globex Trading Application
- Performed Acceptance and Regression Tests

### Birlasoft Ltd. Bangalore, India;

Danbury, CT, USA Client: General Electric – Commercial Finance)

Aug 2007 - Mar 2009

### **Software Engineer**

- Worked in full life cycle (SDLC) in various stages of the project including analysis, user acceptance testing, SQL data mining and defect tracking
- Provided troubleshooting in various domains across multiple Siebel applications including Oracle databases (Production Servers)
- Coordinated with onsite and offshore teams and handled the onsite workload while being the only resource

### Projects

Website: <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/ashwinigprojects/">https://sites.google.com/view/ashwinigprojects/</a>

Github: <a href="https://github.com/anaik12">https://github.com/anaik12</a>

### **Publications**

- ☐ IEEE Gem 2019 Virtual Slot Games for Rehabilitation Exercises https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8811546
- Journal of NeuroScience Research 2022 V-NeuroStack: Open-source 3D time stack software for identifying patterns in neuronal data <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/jnr.25139">https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/jnr.25139</a>
- Neuroscience (SfN) 2019 V-NeuroStack: 3-D time stacks for finding patterns in spontaneous activity of neurons in mouse brain slice <a href="https://www.abstractsonline.com/pp8/#!/7883/presentation/49635">https://www.abstractsonline.com/pp8/#!/7883/presentation/49635</a>